<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Paul Simmering&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>/categories/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Paul Simmering&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Data frame wars: Choosing a Python dataframe library as a dplyr user</title>
      <link>/blog/dataframes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/dataframes/</guid>
      <description>I’m a long time R user and lately I’ve seen more and more signals that it’s worth investing into Python. I use it for NLP with spaCy and to build functions on AWS Lambda. Further, there are many more data API libraries and machine learning libraries for Python than for R.
Adopting Python means making choices on which libraries to invest time into learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmention</title>
      <link>/project/cosmention/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/cosmention/</guid>
      <description>An AI-powered social media monitoring tool for the cosmetics industry. A fully automated data pipeline starting from social media APIs and ending in a customizable dashboard.
I am the inventor and lead developer and started the project as an independent SaaS offering. It was acquired by Q Insight Agency and is now in use at dm, the largest drug store chain in Europe.
I presented the data pipeline in 2021 at the BVM (German association of social and market researchers) symposium on artificial intelligence and wrote an article on Marktforschung.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>StakeX - Organizational Networks from Web Research</title>
      <link>/project/stakex/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/stakex/</guid>
      <description>StakeX is a network analysis approach for public relations projects. It is in use at Q Insight Agency with clients in public transportation and the energy sector. The approach consists of:
 methods for gathering public data on relevant stakeholders building a network based on sociological theory analyzing the network through use of force-based layout algorithms and centrality statistics extracting valuable insights for customers  To learn more about the method, see the talk by Thomas Perry and me or check the methods section of the demo app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring echarts4r</title>
      <link>/blog/echarts4r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/echarts4r/</guid>
      <description>As web-oriented presentation in R Markdown and Shiny becomes more and more popular, there is increasing demand for interactive graphics with R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Patent Explorer</title>
      <link>/project/gpexp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/gpexp/</guid>
      <description>Freeelance work for Aalborg University, commissioned by Assoc. Prof. Daniel S. Hain and Assoc. Prof. Roman Jurowetzki. It visualizes the results of a paper on natural language processing on patent texts:
 D.S. Hain, R. Jurowetzki, T. Buchmann, P. Wolf (2018), A Vector Worth a Thousand Counts: A Temporal Semantic Similarity Approach to Patent Impact Prediction. Available at http://vbn.aau.dk/en/publications/a-vector-worth-a-thousand-counts(855d9758-d017-4b4a-baf5-8b7e72a1c223).html
 This tool lets users map and visualize inventive and innovative activity around the globe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human and AI Decision Making in a Game of Innovation and Imitation</title>
      <link>/project/masterthesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/masterthesis/</guid>
      <description>My master thesis investigates the use of artificial intelligence (AI) in managerial decision making. The thesis was supervised by Assoc. Prof. Daniel S. Hain and Assoc. Prof. Roman Jurowetzki at Aalborg University.
Current AI is narrow, specialized for single tasks and cannot be applied to others. However, recent developments in general game-playing algorithms suggest that AI will become more generally applicable. In managerial decision making, it could be used as a decision support systems or as an autonomous decision maker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do Internet Users have a Positive Willingness-To-Pay for Ad-free Usage of Websites?</title>
      <link>/project/bachelorthesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/bachelorthesis/</guid>
      <description>I conducted an online survey and economic experiment and analyzed the results using logistic regression. The thesis was supervised by Prof. Dr. Gerhard Riener at University of Mannheim.
Photo by Justus Menke on Unsplash</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
