<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Python on Paul Simmering&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>/categories/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Python on Paul Simmering&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Data frame wars: pandas vs. polars vs duckdb</title>
      <link>/blog/dataframes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/dataframes/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a long time R user and lately I&amp;rsquo;ve seen more and more signals that it&amp;rsquo;s worth investing into learning more Python. I use it for NLP with spaCy and to build functions on AWS Lambda (though the recent lambdr package gave R some great tools there too). Further, there are many more data API libraries available for Python than for R.
The contenders     The first thing I needed was a way to manipulate data frames.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmention</title>
      <link>/project/cosmention/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/cosmention/</guid>
      <description>An AI-powered social media monitoring tool for the cosmetics industry. A fully automated data pipeline starting from social media APIs and ending in a customizable dashboard.
I am the inventor and lead developer and started the project as an independent SaaS offering. It was acquired by Q Insight Agency and is now in use at dm, the largest drug store chain in Europe.
I presented the data pipeline in 2021 at the BVM (German association of social and market researchers) symposium on artificial intelligence and wrote an article on Marktforschung.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
