<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Paul Simmering on Paul Simmering&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Paul Simmering on Paul Simmering&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Netlify</title>
      <link>/collection/day02/01-netlify/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/collection/day02/01-netlify/</guid>
      <description>So far, we&amp;rsquo;ve been leveraging GitHub Pages for publishing. This works great, but for blogdown we&amp;rsquo;ll start using Netlify. Let&amp;rsquo;s start RIGHT NOW with a site we&amp;rsquo;ve already built and published.
Pre-requisites     Pick either your postcards site, or your distill site from day 01. Refresh your memory- which repository was it again?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A GitHub profile</title>
      <link>/collection/day01/01-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/collection/day01/01-github/</guid>
      <description>Profile      https://docs.github.com/en/github/setting-up-and-managing-your-github-profile/personalizing-your-profile
Pin projects to profile      https://docs.github.com/en/github/setting-up-and-managing-your-github-profile/pinning-items-to-your-profile
Profile README     This is new! Let&amp;rsquo;s do it:
 https://docs.github.com/en/github/setting-up-and-managing-your-github-profile/managing-your-profile-readme</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prework</title>
      <link>/collection/prework/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/collection/prework/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the Introducing Yourself Online workshop! We look forward to meeting you. Before attending the workshop, please complete the following prework.
Set up RStudio Cloud     Sign up for a free RStudio Cloud account at https://rstudio.cloud/ before the workshop. I recommend logging in with an existing Google or GitHub account, if you have one (rather than creating a new account with another password you have to remember).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A postcard</title>
      <link>/collection/day01/02-postcards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/collection/day01/02-postcards/</guid>
      <description>Pre-requisites     First, make sure you have the latest version of the postcards package installed from CRAN:
install.packages(&amp;quot;postcards&amp;quot;) Restart your R session. If you use RStudio, use the menu item Session &amp;gt; Restart R or the associated keyboard shortcut:
 Ctrl + Shift + F10 (Windows and Linux) or Command + Shift + F10 (Mac OS).  packageVersion(&amp;quot;postcards&amp;quot;) [1] ‘0.2.0’  Create GitHub repo     Online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using blogdown</title>
      <link>/collection/day02/02-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/collection/day02/02-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>Pre-requisites     First, make sure you have the latest version of the blogdown package installed from CRAN:
install.packages(&amp;quot;blogdoown&amp;quot;) Restart your R session. If you use RStudio, use the menu item Session &amp;gt; Restart R or the associated keyboard shortcut:
 Ctrl + Shift + F10 (Windows and Linux) or Command + Shift + F10 (Mac OS).  packageVersion(&amp;quot;blogdown&amp;quot;) [1] ‘1.0’  Create GitHub repo     Online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A distill site</title>
      <link>/collection/day01/03-distill/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/collection/day01/03-distill/</guid>
      <description>Pre-requisites     First, make sure you have the latest version of the distill package installed from CRAN:
install.packages(&amp;quot;distill&amp;quot;)  Restart your R session. If you use RStudio, use the menu item Session &amp;gt; Restart R or the associated keyboard shortcut:
 Ctrl + Shift + F10 (Windows and Linux) or Command + Shift + F10 (Mac OS).  &amp;lt;!-- --&amp;gt; packageVersion(&amp;quot;distill&amp;quot;) [1] ‘1.2’  Create GitHub repo     Online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Warm woolen mittens</title>
      <link>/collection/day02/03-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/collection/day02/03-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I&#39;m the here-bot cat! Use me to find your way in your website.
Here I am: content/collection/day02/03-blogdown/index.md  To remove me, delete this line inside that file: {{&amp;lt; here &amp;gt;}}
My content section is: collection  My layout is: single-series   part 2!     does this work?      now for some very cool things     more     get ready!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data frame wars: Choosing a Python dataframe library as a dplyr user</title>
      <link>/blog/dataframes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/dataframes/</guid>
      <description>I’m a long time R user and lately I’ve seen more and more signals that it’s worth investing into Python. I use it for NLP with spaCy and to build functions on AWS Lambda. Further, there are many more data API libraries and machine learning libraries for Python than for R.
Adopting Python means making choices on which libraries to invest time into learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FANGMANT: Tech stock analysis with pandas</title>
      <link>/blog/fangmant/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/fangmant/</guid>
      <description>The acronym FANGMANT stands for Facebook, Apple, Netflix, Google, Microsoft, Amazon, Nvidia and Tesla. Large, highly profitable US tech companies that dominate their respective markets. Other common acronyms are FANG, FAANG and FANGMAN.
In this article, I&amp;rsquo;m analyzing their stock performance from 2016 to 2021.
Disclaimer: This article is not financial advice. It&amp;rsquo;s a data analysis for fun.
Download with yfinance      yfinance is a Python package that downloads financial data from Yahoo!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI for Social Media Monitoring at dm</title>
      <link>/talk/bvmki2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/bvmki2021/</guid>
      <description>A presentation on Cosmention&amp;rsquo;s data pipeline and how Cosmention is used at dm, the largest drugstore chain in Europe. The presentation starts with a review of language models and word vectors and then dives into text classification and named entity recognition.
Photo by Christopher Burns on Unsplash</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmention</title>
      <link>/project/cosmention/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/cosmention/</guid>
      <description>An AI-powered social media monitoring tool for the cosmetics industry. A fully automated data pipeline starting from social media APIs and ending in a customizable dashboard.
I am the inventor and lead developer and started the project as an independent SaaS offering. It was acquired by Q Insight Agency and is now in use at dm, the largest drug store chain in Europe.
I presented the data pipeline in 2021 at the BVM (German association of social and market researchers) symposium on artificial intelligence and wrote an article on Marktforschung.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>StakeX - Organizational Networks from Web Research</title>
      <link>/project/stakex/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/stakex/</guid>
      <description>StakeX is a network analysis approach for public relations projects. It is in use at Q Insight Agency with clients in public transportation and the energy sector. The approach consists of:
 methods for gathering public data on relevant stakeholders building a network based on sociological theory analyzing the network through use of force-based layout algorithms and centrality statistics extracting valuable insights for customers  To learn more about the method, see the talk by Thomas Perry and me or check the methods section of the demo app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>StakeX - Organizational Networks from Web Research</title>
      <link>/talk/comes2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/comes2020/</guid>
      <description>Thomas Perry and me presented the StakeX method, which was developed at Q Insight Agency.
Photo by Alina Grubnyak on Unsplash</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring echarts4r</title>
      <link>/blog/echarts4r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/echarts4r/</guid>
      <description>As web-oriented presentation in R Markdown and Shiny becomes more and more popular, there is increasing demand for interactive graphics with R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Shiny for Interactive Data Visualization – A Case Study</title>
      <link>/talk/gor2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/gor2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 13:38:41 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>** Contact page don&amp;rsquo;t contain a body, just the front matter above. See form.html in the layouts folder.
Formspree requires a (free) account and new form to be set up. The link is made on the final published url in the field: Restrict to Domain. It is possible to register up to 2 emails free and you can select which one you want the forms to go to within Formspree in the Settings tab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Typography Styles &amp; Element Examples</title>
      <link>/elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 12:27:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/elements/</guid>
      <description>Font Sizes   A A A A A A A A   6rem
(96px) 5rem
(80px) 3rem
(48px) 2.25rem
(36px) 1.5rem
(24px) 1.25rem
(20px) 1rem
(16px) .875rem
(14px)     Type Samples Head&amp;shy;line Sub&amp;shy;head&amp;shy;line Level 1 Heading One page to rule them all...well, not really. This page displays sample typography and page elements to illustrate their style. Things like headings and paragraphs showing the beautiful type scale, form elements, tabular data, and image layouts just to name a few.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human and AI Decision Making in a Game of Innovation and Imitation.</title>
      <link>/talk/researchplus2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/researchplus2018/</guid>
      <description>A presentation of the research project I conducted at Aalborg University for my master thesis. I investigated the use of artificial intelligence (AI) in managerial decision making by example of a business game. Six human participants competed against an AI agent. The agent combines Monte Carlo Tree Search with prediction of outcomes using an artificial neural network. While playing, human participants gave a think-aloud protocol. Among other results, the study found architectural parallels in thought processes, qualitative differences in decisions due to AI&amp;rsquo;s lack of reciprocity, and potential problems in value alignment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Patent Explorer</title>
      <link>/project/gpexp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/gpexp/</guid>
      <description>Freeelance work for Aalborg University, commissioned by Assoc. Prof. Daniel S. Hain and Assoc. Prof. Roman Jurowetzki. It visualizes the results of a paper on natural language processing on patent texts:
 D.S. Hain, R. Jurowetzki, T. Buchmann, P. Wolf (2018), A Vector Worth a Thousand Counts: A Temporal Semantic Similarity Approach to Patent Impact Prediction. Available at http://vbn.aau.dk/en/publications/a-vector-worth-a-thousand-counts(855d9758-d017-4b4a-baf5-8b7e72a1c223).html
 This tool lets users map and visualize inventive and innovative activity around the globe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human and AI Decision Making in a Game of Innovation and Imitation</title>
      <link>/project/masterthesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/masterthesis/</guid>
      <description>My master thesis investigates the use of artificial intelligence (AI) in managerial decision making. The thesis was supervised by Assoc. Prof. Daniel S. Hain and Assoc. Prof. Roman Jurowetzki at Aalborg University.
Current AI is narrow, specialized for single tasks and cannot be applied to others. However, recent developments in general game-playing algorithms suggest that AI will become more generally applicable. In managerial decision making, it could be used as a decision support systems or as an autonomous decision maker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Innovation and Imitation Strategies in the Age of the Upgrade – An Agent-Based Simulation Model</title>
      <link>/talk/concordi2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/concordi2017/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Joan Oger on Unsplash</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Innovation and Imitation Strategies in the Age of the Upgrade – An Agent-Based Simulation Model</title>
      <link>/talk/emaee2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/emaee2017/</guid>
      <description>Product life-cycles in markets for innovative products are shortening, con- sumers rapidly upgrade from one product generation to the next and demand constant technical improvement. Firms are racing against each other and the consumers’ rising ex- pectations. This study uses an agent-based simulation model to analyze the dynamics of innovation and imitation strategies in this new type of market from the firm perspective. Firms use pure and mixed strategies to achieve maximum profitability over the life-cycle of a market for a new product category.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do Internet Users have a Positive Willingness-To-Pay for Ad-free Usage of Websites?</title>
      <link>/project/bachelorthesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/bachelorthesis/</guid>
      <description>I conducted an online survey and economic experiment and analyzed the results using logistic regression. The thesis was supervised by Prof. Dr. Gerhard Riener at University of Mannheim.
Photo by Justus Menke on Unsplash</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impressum</title>
      <link>/impressum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/impressum/</guid>
      <description>Informationspflicht laut § 5 TMG.
Paul Simmering
Email: paul.simmering@gmail.com
Weinheimer Str. 20, 68519 Viernheim</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
