<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data science blog on Paul Simmering&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data science blog on Paul Simmering&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Data frame wars: Choosing a Python dataframe library as a dplyr user</title>
      <link>/blog/dataframes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/dataframes/</guid>
      <description>I’m a long time R user and lately I’ve seen more and more signals that it’s worth investing into Python. I use it for NLP with spaCy and to build functions on AWS Lambda. Further, there are many more data API libraries and machine learning libraries for Python than for R.
Adopting Python means making choices on which libraries to invest time into learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FANGMANT: Tech stock analysis with pandas</title>
      <link>/blog/fangmant/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/fangmant/</guid>
      <description>The acronym FANGMANT stands for Facebook, Apple, Netflix, Google, Microsoft, Amazon, Nvidia and Tesla. Large, highly profitable US tech companies that dominate their respective markets. Other common acronyms are FANG, FAANG and FANGMAN.
In this article, I&amp;rsquo;m analyzing their stock performance from 2016 to 2021.
Disclaimer: This article is not financial advice. It&amp;rsquo;s a data analysis for fun.
Download with yfinance      yfinance is a Python package that downloads financial data from Yahoo!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring echarts4r</title>
      <link>/blog/echarts4r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/echarts4r/</guid>
      <description>As web-oriented presentation in R Markdown and Shiny becomes more and more popular, there is increasing demand for interactive graphics with R.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
